tcc.edu 2019-10-24

# Website Privacy Statement - TCC.edu

## Scope

This Privacy Statement applies only to official, public-facing TCC Websites (“Websites”) on the [tcc.edu](http://www.tcc.edu/) domain and [www.tccenroll.com](http://www.tccenroll.com/).

## Links to Third-Party Websites

The Websites may contain links to third-party sites or apps. If you follow a link to any of these third-party sites or apps, please note that they, and any services accessible through them, are not covered by this Privacy Statement. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Websites and to read the privacy policies applicable to those third-party sites or apps.

## Privacy Statement Changes

This Privacy Statement may be revised in the future. The updated Privacy Statement will be posted on the Websites with a new Revised Date. We encourage you to review the Privacy Statement periodically.

## What Information We Collect

### Personal Information

This is information you directly and voluntarily provide to us, such as when you submit a form requesting information about one of our programs. Information we directly collect may include your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address and other information you voluntarily provide.

### Non-Personal Information

This is aggregate information automatically collected when you visit the Websites. This may include your IP address and domain name, general geographic location (as inferred from your IP address), your internet service provider, the date and time of your visit to the Websites, your use of the Websites during your current session and over time (including the pages you view and the files you download), the URLs from sites you visit before and after navigating to the Websites, your computer or device’s operating system, browser type and version, and software and hardware attributes.

## How We Collect Information

We collect Personal Information only when you voluntarily provide it to us. We automatically collect Non-Personal Information using the following methods:

### Server logs

When you visit the Websites, we automatically receive and record certain information from your computer or device and your browser. This may include data such as your IP address, operating system, browser type and version, the pages you visit, or features you use on the Website, and general geographic location (as inferred from your IP address).

### Cookies & pixels

These Websites use cookies and pixels. When you use the Websites, cookies are placed in the browser files of your computer or mobile device. A cookie is a piece of data stored on your computer hard drive containing information about you. Pixels are small pieces of code on webpages often are used in connection with cookies that allow us to track the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns.

We use cookies for performance monitoring, analytics and marketing purposes. Below are the types of cookies that may be used on the Websites:

##### Performance cookies

Cookies placed by tools we use to monitor the Websites’ performance and visitor behavior on the Websites.

##### Advertising cookies

We sometimes use tracking pixels that assist us with delivering targeted online advertising. By better understanding what our audiences are interested in, we can more efficiently promote the College.

##### Facebook﻿

We use Facebook tracking pixels to collect visitor data on the Websites and later serve relevant advertising on Facebook and Instagram.

##### Google Adwords and Google Display Network

We use Google Adwords tracking cookies to serve relevant advertising and measure advertising performance (on third-party sites) based on visits to the Websites.

##### Link tracking

Our marketing emails contain a number of hyperlinks, each of which has a unique tag. When you click on one of these links, you are automatically redirected to the server of our email service which logs the click. From there you are redirected to the relevant page on the Websites. This process enables us to measure the number of clicks from an email resulting in visits to the Websites. We use this information to tailor future messages to users.

##### Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to provide us with insight into how users are accessing the Websites’ pages, and users’ activity around the Websites. User data does not include Personal Information, but does include things like city location, browser and platforms used, and aggregated demographic information from users’ Google profiles such as gender, age-bracket and interests.

##### AdRoll

We use the AdRoll display advertising network to collect visitor data on the Websites, serve targeted display ads, and measure advertising performance on other sites.

## How We Use Information

The College uses information available in the Websites’ server logs and cookies to:

  * measure performance of the College’s Websites and online advertising
  * provide interest-based advertising messages
  * inform development of new content and functionality on the Websites

We use the Personal Information that you voluntarily provide on the Websites to correspond directly with you, and send you promotional communications about the College’s programs.

## Data Retention Period

We strive to keep personal data in our records only as long as they are necessary for the purposes they were collected and processed. Retention periods vary and are established considering our legitimate purposes and all applicable legal requirements.

## Disclosure of Information

We may share your Personal Information when required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process; when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of the College community, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

The College does not sell or rent your Personal Information. We may, however, share your Personal Information with third-party service providers in limited circumstances to support the College’s business activities. We use third-party service providers to help us manage and improve the Websites and our marketing efforts. We provide these parties with only the information they need to perform their services and work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected. These service providers may collect and/or use your information to assist us in achieving the purposes discussed in this Privacy Statement. For example, we use third parties to deliver marketing communications and serve online ads.

The use of online tracking mechanisms by third parties is subject to those third parties’ own privacy policies, and not this Privacy Statement. If you prefer to prevent third parties from setting and accessing cookies on your computer, you may set your browser to block cookies.

### Your Choices and Access to Information

  * For more information on how Google protects your data visit [Safeguarding Your Data](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631).
  * You may opt out of the [use of cookies by Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * You can opt-out of [Google Display Network ads](https://adssettings.google.com/) by using Ad settings provided by Google
  * View information on [Facebook’s Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation) and learn how to [control online ads from Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950).

Additionally, you may remove yourself from the targeted advertising of companies within the [Network Advertising Initiative by opting out here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/), or of companies participating in the [Digital Advertising Alliance program by opting out here](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN).

If you no longer want to receive marketing communications from TCC, please follow the unsubscribe instructions that are included at the bottom of each message. Please note that if you unsubscribe from our marketing communications, you may still receive administrative messages from the College.

Depending on your location and where applicable law requires, you may have the following choices with respect to your Personal Information submitted on the Websites covered by this Privacy Statement:

  * The right to access your Personal Information;
  * The right to update your Personal Information by emailing us;
  * The right to withdraw your consent to providing Personal Information
  * The right to request deletion of your Personal Information or object to its processing; and
  * The right to lodge a complaint with an applicable supervisory authority.

If you would like to exercise your choices regarding the Personal Information collected on the Websites, please contact us by email at [webcomm@tcc.edu](mailto:webcomm@tcc.edu?subject=Data%20Opt%20Out).

## Security

TCC recognizes the importance of maintaining the security of the information it collects and maintains. The College uses physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to procedures in place to safeguard the information we collect from you, including (but not limited to):

  * SSL Website encryption
  * Software programs that monitor network traffic, identify unauthorized access or access to non-public information, detect computer viruses and other software that might damage College computers and the network, and also monitor the performance of the College network.

When you email us, the possibility exists, however remote, that your message may be intercepted by an unauthorized person or entity. You should never use email to send personal data (such as financial information) to us.

Please be aware that, although we endeavor provide reasonable security for information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches.

## Children

These Websites are not directed to persons under 13. If you are a minor between the ages of 13 and 18, you may use these Websites only in conjunction with your parent, legal guardian or other responsible adult. If you become aware that your child has provided us with Personal Information on these Websites without your consent, please contact us at [webcomm@tcc.edu](mailto:webcomm@tcc.edu?subject=COPPA%20). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we take steps to remove such information.

* * *

_Updated July 9, 2018_
